<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PaulRz</title>
    <link>https://paulrz.cz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on PaulRz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://paulrz.cz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Curious Case of Dave and the AWOL Secondary Node</title>
      <link>https://paulrz.cz/posts/pg-kill-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paulrz.cz/posts/pg-kill-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: This fairy tale is generated by ChatGPT based on true story.
Once upon a time in the quirky land of Databasia, there existed a splendid PostgreSQL cluster. It was a harmonious symphony of data, with a Primary node leading the ensemble and a Secondary node providing the sweet, reassuring notes of redundancy. Life was good, data flowed seamlessly, and administrators everywhere slept soundly.
However, every paradise has its serpent. In this case, it was a curious admin named Dave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL and updates</title>
      <link>https://paulrz.cz/posts/pg-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paulrz.cz/posts/pg-hot/</guid>
      <description>In many database applications, particularly in workflow systems, there’s a common requirement to update the status of records. These statuses could range from &amp;ldquo;ready to process&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;processing,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;done,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;reprocessing,&amp;rdquo; or even &amp;ldquo;urgently needed to be processed.&amp;rdquo; While updating a row may seem trivial in some databases like Oracle, it becomes more complex and nuanced in PostgreSQL. What may appear as a simple status change at the application level actually involves several hidden processes that can lead to performance degradation over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenZFS and Ubuntu tweaks</title>
      <link>https://paulrz.cz/posts/ubuntu-tweaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paulrz.cz/posts/ubuntu-tweaks/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I embarked on a project to optimize my home server setup by transitioning my disk storage pool from RAID5 using mdadm and XFS to ZFS RAIDZ-1. Honestly, it’s been a huge improvement in both performance and functionality, and I’m pretty excited about the results so far. My home server functions as a lab environment, where I primarily serve videos, experiment with Kubernetes clusters, and run various virtual machines (VMs) — mostly OpenBSD and FreeBSD instances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an OpenBSD Box for Vagrant: A Personal Guide</title>
      <link>https://paulrz.cz/posts/openbsd-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paulrz.cz/posts/openbsd-box/</guid>
      <description>As someone who enjoys exploring different operating systems, I often find myself setting up environments in OpenBSD. It&amp;rsquo;s an elegant and minimalist OS with a strong emphasis on security, which makes it ideal for a variety of use cases. Recently, I worked on creating an OpenBSD box for Vagrant, and I thought I’d share the step-by-step process I followed, along with a few quirks and tips I discovered along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up an IPv6 Tunnel with OpenBSD</title>
      <link>https://paulrz.cz/posts/ipv6-he/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paulrz.cz/posts/ipv6-he/</guid>
      <description>Though IPv6 has been around for quite some time, its adoption is still not as widespread as IPv4. While IPv6 offers an almost unlimited number of addresses, support from major ISPs remains limited. One way to enable IPv6 at home is by using a tunnel broker like Hurricane Electric, which provides a routable IPv6 prefix to your home network.
In this guide, we’ll configure an IPv6 tunnel on OpenBSD 7.5, using it as a home router.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey from Oracle to PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://paulrz.cz/posts/pg-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paulrz.cz/posts/pg-intro/</guid>
      <description>From the start of my career, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been deep into Oracle Database, working on versions from 8i to 12c, all focused on online transaction processing (OLTP). Oracle is rock solid—safe, reliable, and, as Ask Tom will tell you, simply great. There’s even a saying in the industry: “You’ve never gotten in trouble by buying Oracle.” And for the longest time, that was my truth.
In the OLTP world, you deal with loads that demand low latency and high transaction rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rigging The Game by Dan Nicholson (1/N)</title>
      <link>https://paulrz.cz/posts/rigging-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paulrz.cz/posts/rigging-the-game/</guid>
      <description>Dan Nicholson&amp;rsquo;s Rigging the Game offers a unique perspective on how to achieve financial certainty in a world filled with unpredictability. The core idea? Many people choose to remain in the &amp;ldquo;certainty of misery&amp;rdquo; rather than face the &amp;ldquo;misery of uncertainty.&amp;rdquo; But are you one of those people? Nicholson invites us to reconsider how we approach decisions, especially in business and finance, and provides a set of principles designed to help us rig the game in our favor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://paulrz.cz/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paulrz.cz/about/</guid>
      <description>Management skills: 🔗 Agile mindset, Scrum, Scrum of Scrums, LeSS, Experienced Product Owner and Scrum Master, Couching, Mentoring, Servant Leadership, Onboarding, People Management, People Development, Project Management - PRINCE2© Foundation Certificate. Business Areas: 🔗 Telecommunications - 3GPP standards, SIP, VoIP, Billing, Online Charging, Security - Authentication, Encryption, Public Key Infrastructure, Security Audits, BPM - Pega Certified Senior Software Architect (7.4). AI - Deep Learning course of Andrew Ng Languages and APIs: 🔗 C#, ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
