<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>architecture on PaulRz</title>
    <link>https://paulrz.cz/tags/architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in architecture on PaulRz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://paulrz.cz/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Haskell for Enterprise Architecture</title>
      <link>https://paulrz.cz/posts/ea-haskell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paulrz.cz/posts/ea-haskell/</guid>
      <description>I was playing with an idea that Haskell might be a right language to describe an Enterprise Architecture. Haskell’s strong type system, functional programming paradigm, and support for domain-specific languages (DSLs) make it a good candidate for modeling enterprise architecture (EA). Here’s why and how:
Why Haskell is Suitable for Enterprise Architecture: 🔗 Strong Typing &amp;amp; Type Safety: Enterprise architecture models deal with various interconnected components (like applications, data, infrastructure, processes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Architecture Artifacts and Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://paulrz.cz/posts/ea-artifacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paulrz.cz/posts/ea-artifacts/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) involves a structured approach to aligning IT infrastructure and business processes with organizational goals. To support this, various artifacts are created that serve as models, documentation, and representations of the organization’s systems. These artifacts help communicate, plan, and govern the architecture across different stakeholders. The main artifacts of enterprise architecture typically fall into several categories:
Business Architecture Artifacts Business Capability Model: A high-level map of the organization’s abilities to meet business goals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
