<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technical sidenotes on PaulRz</title>
    <link>https://paulrz.cz/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technical sidenotes on PaulRz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://paulrz.cz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OpenZFS and Ubuntu tweaks</title>
      <link>https://paulrz.cz/posts/ubuntu-tweaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paulrz.cz/posts/ubuntu-tweaks/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I embarked on a project to optimize my home server setup by transitioning my disk storage pool from RAID5 using mdadm and XFS to ZFS RAIDZ-1. Honestly, it’s been a huge improvement in both performance and functionality, and I’m pretty excited about the results so far. My home server functions as a lab environment, where I primarily serve videos, experiment with Kubernetes clusters, and run various virtual machines (VMs) — mostly OpenBSD and FreeBSD instances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huricane Electric IPv6 tunnel broker</title>
      <link>https://paulrz.cz/posts/ipv6-he/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paulrz.cz/posts/ipv6-he/</guid>
      <description>IPv6 is quite old technology but its adoptions is not as widespread as IPv4. Blessed with virtually unlimited number of addresses, it still lacks support on major internet service providers. But one might use a tunnel to Hurricane Electric to get a routable prefix to his home network.
Last days I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying OpenBSD 7.5 and use it as a home lab and a home router. So let&amp;rsquo;s start!
Configure tunnel 🔗You provide your public IP to HE and you get the something like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL and its quirks</title>
      <link>https://paulrz.cz/posts/pg-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paulrz.cz/posts/pg-intro/</guid>
      <description>From the beginning of my career I&amp;rsquo;ve always been working with Oracle Database, from 8i till 12c, on online transaction processing (OLTP). The database is safe, reliable and - Ask Tom! - it&amp;rsquo;s great. And as saying goes, &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rsquo;ve never got in trouble by buying Oracle&amp;rdquo;.
OLTP loads usually require low latency and high transaction rate. Under different load profiles it was quite simple to come up with a solution of any performance problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
